When Musk was acquiring Twitter, there
was recognition that there is this
window of opportunity.
>> This is Sash. He grew to staff at Meta
despite switching teams 10 times in 9
years. Two diffs in 6 months. What was
your performance review like in in that?
>> I wanted to share this conversation so
you could learn about how switching
teams can affect your career.
>> What was your thinking behind wanting to
shift to such a different domain?
>> Android is like terrifying for anyone
who builds for iOS. They're like, "God
forbids you go there."
>> Eventually, you went to a series of
teams that I'm really interested in.
>> For viewers at home, Instagram used to
have a blockchain team. You started work
on a very experimental interesting
project for a while. We had this as a
secret inside of Instagram.
>> Well, let's start at the beginning of
the story. So, how did you pick the
first team and what was the story behind
that? Well, my first pick was this team
based in London and they were like, "Oh,
yeah, we're going to work remote and
it's going to be fine." But the code
review times with London, they would
take like days. And so I ended up sort
of deciding against that. And I chatted
with this one guy, he's also still at
the company. And he saw my sort of
resume or whatever, and he saw that I'm
sort of like a weird hybrid of like
design and engineering and like
everything is kind of poorly defined.
And he was like, "Listen, how about
this? We're going to build a team that
takes all the design prototypes that
designers always have like stacked up in
their desk but never shipped, right? And
we're just going to build them and no
metrics, no nothing. And it was inside
of newsfeed, uh, Facebook newsfeed. I
mean, now if I would look back and I
would hear newsfeed, no metrics, I would
be like, "Oh yeah, this team is going to
survive half a year." And it survived
half a year. Uh, but it was so much fun.
It was a lot of fun. And like the the
value prop was just so fun to me because
it was like oh let's build the right
thing and not worry about metrics and
the things that we built later we found
some metrics to like to associate with
that. Again it didn't survive longterm
scrutiny but it was a lot of fun. It was
all sort of really joyful projects. The
team was called newsfeed delight and uh
yeah I was just building all sort of
like fun visual animations effects
that's like sort of what people usually
call Easter eggs in the apps. We were
building that and it was so much fun
because again every designer dreams of
that but then every engineer looks at it
through lens of impact and they're like
I'm not touching this with it like you
know. Yeah. And like the the other theme
through my career was that I'm just not
thinking about impact too well and that
allows me to pick the teams that are
completely irrational and like high risk
and like god knows if there is even
reward in that. I saw those teams that
you worked on initially, the design
ones, and I was thinking how how do you
measure success or how do you prove that
this prototype was a good idea?
>> Yeah.
>> If there's it's kind of going off of
vibe. So I'm curious like what does a
successful project even look like in a
>> So I think in in the spaces like that
now I can rationalize how it's done in a
company like Meta, right? So you have
some executive sponsor with some sort of
theory that like they justify to someone
and and that's basically how those teams
survive. So Facebook used to have this
metric called cow cares about user and
this metric was literally a survey
issued in a news feed that would ask you
like some some broad question of like oh
do you feel like Facebook cares about
you and this highly subjective metric
that like I'm not even sure if you can
like if everyone understands it in the
same way was what a lot of teams were
orienting towards and so this kind of
laded into that I guess to some degree
especially in today's world where you
want everything to be highly efficient
and there is not too much time to focus
on on this like moments of delight and
joy. Uh yeah, it's sort of like harder
to to justify existence of those kind of
teams. I feel like you
>> you mentioned you weren't optimizing for
impact at that point and it sounds like
throughout your career that's a common
thing. What were you optimizing for in
that team choice?
>> Fun, you know, just like pure fun. I I'm
I'm sort of
I often end up in the situations where
looking back I'm like oh that was lucky
that was cool and you just meet people
and you you explore some opportunities
and later again sort of like looking
back they all make sense mostly because
proactively you don't know what's going
to happen but also you end up building
you know accumulating this toolbox
skills people connections you know like
all all those things and that you can
build upon later and so yeah I feel like
I'm joining a team because I have some
intuition of like, oh, this might be fun
interesting slash whatever. Later in
career, I became a bit more intentional,
but still sort of optimizing for this
riskyish space like 0ero to one space. I
think that what I noticed early on and
that was again sort of coming from
startup days is that a lot of people are
sort of uncomfortable with ambiguity.
They're uncomfortable with poorly
defined spaces. You know, sort of like
ambiguous spaces, no product definition,
no direction. And a lot of people
they're really good engineers but they
need this sort of like oh like this is
what we need this is the diagram this is
the mock whatever where maybe because of
the design pass maybe whatever I would
always be like oh yeah we can kind of
yolo it as we go right and and sooner
rather than later you realize that it's
an asset you know when when you can be
effective in this environment that's
sort of challenging or ambiguous to
others it's an asset that you can use
and then then it's a question of yeah
like how do you measure this
effectiveness? you had a lot of
opportunities to work with different
designers. I'm kind of curious from an
engineers perspective. What makes the
best designers to work with?
>> I think it's just the collaboration um
sort of process. So the most fun I have
is with and it's not just designers but
designersh in in in your context
specifically is that you have people who
are readily sort of jam with you. they
they don't just come up with this idea
in a vacuum because often times for
better and for worse it's not informed
with real world constraints nor should
it be but then when you have this design
initial design it's like oh but what
happens when when your network fails or
what happens when when user doesn't have
this field in their d whatever so like
you you need this constant dance between
like here is this idea that we want to
to achieve and here is the the real
world inputs often times what I would
find even more fun is when you you show
designers oh like look at all those cool
capab abilities that we can actually use
in your design. So like what if we like
at the time like I don't know what if
you use some sort of like location to
inform how this looks or if you use
accelerometer of the device to to to
move the the shadows different way. It's
like all the stuff that not every
designer necessarily knows or remembers
off top of their head is is a fun way to
sort of to inform the creations. But
then also the iteration loop like in my
experience the tighter you can get the
iteration loop the better. And I had a
few projects on some unreleased pieces
of hardware where the whole thing was
for me to build a hacky version of Figma
2 unreleased device rendering pipeline
so the designers can just like see their
Figas on and release device as quickly
as possible and just like move stuff
around and like infinite immediately see
it being reflected. So like all this
iteration loops the shorter they are the
better and the more both partners
engineers designers whoever else is
involved are ready to to hear each other
and like sort of internalize the
constraints and sort of talk about it
the stronger products come out.
>> So if I'm understanding correctly uh you
mentioned the short the short iteration
loop but also it's kind of like this
birectional communication like
engineering might propose something that
design doesn't know design does the same
and
>> the end result is a much better product.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, for sure. I also find
it really helpful when you just start
the project to like not involve
technical constraints too much and just
be like, "Okay, cool. Yeah, we're going
to build this crazy thing that you
want." And then you sort of then you can
trim it down to to meet the world where
the world is, right? So like if it's
hardware, well, what is the I don't know
like thermal envelope that you have to
work against? Well, maybe the device is
just going to blow up if it runs so so
for so long or you know maybe yeah like
processing power is not there so it
cannot be as real time as designer. like
you know all sort of real life
constraints that will get in the way
anyway. But yeah, it definitely helps to
start with a pretty you know sort of
like everything is going to be working
the way you want and then sort of like
inform each other and sort of bounce off
each other and like this definitely
builds a stronger product. So I think
like that first leg of your career you
were working on like traditional iOS
kind of things very designoriented and I
understand that you pivoted at some
point more towards a completely
different domain. You switched teams uh
multiple times even with within iOS but
then you switched to an entirely
different domain in hardware and
prototyping experimental hardware.
>> What was your thinking behind wanting to
shift to such a different domain? I was
just looking for a new sort of team and
I started by looking at you know your
iOS teams we have this internal jobs
tool I was looking for something in New
York and I just couldn't find anything
that was sort of appealing enough but
then there was this one of the postings
was like oh we're like starting this new
hardware team and there was not really
that much information like that's at the
time the internal job tool was like sort
of like semi updated once in the blue
moon I think now it's like more rigorous
but yeah and So I reached out and turns
out that they were looking for people to
work on hardware based off of Android
open source OS. So like AOSP it's like
pretty standard practice I think right
now if you're like building new device
you just start with this AOSP sort of
OS. I think I sort of just switched to
it because like oh there is nothing more
fun in New York for me right now. Why
not? Obviously zero experience with
hardware or Android. Android is like
terrifying for anyone who builds for
iOS. They're like god forbids you ever
go there. It's like going to the dark
side. But yeah, so I ended up switching
and that team was a lot of fun. It was
like it's like sort of like this Alice
in Wonderland like once you once you
plunge, you know, into the rabbit hole,
you kind of like, oh, this is this is
really fun. And so yeah, I sort of
switched to that team. First half a
year, I think I committed like maybe two
divs in the entire time in six months.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Because because there was
basically no, it was all prototyping. It
was all like okay first we need to to
begin with we we needed to figure out
like what hardware do we even need to
source what kind of processors what's
kind of whatever and it's like you have
bunch of like mobile engineers like
sourcing hardware that's fun yeah in the
meantime we also needed to understand
how this hardware would interact with
sort of like existent hardware ecosystem
so like all your phones all your
whatever so me being sort of aware of
iPhones and iOS sort of ecosystem and
loving reverse engineering stuff. I
started looking into how Apple builds
their messaging stack and sort of how
they communicate. So there is this
protocol that allows you know whenever
you you get into a car that doesn't have
Apple car or like Google car you end up
connecting your phone and you see like
your messages or calls in this like
really old school dashboard. So there is
a protocol that allows you to do that
via Bluetooth. And obviously Apple had
to build their own extension on top of
this protocol that's not really public.
And so it was a fun little project where
I got Raspberry Pi off of somewhere and
I started installing software on it to
pretend that it's a car and pair it with
my phone and like eventually I started
like tracing the the the the packets and
sort of like some information is
publicly available on the internet, some
information you just need to like sort
of reverse engineer. But it was yeah the
the reason why we I didn't commit any of
this code is because like it's a trash
code and like you you don't need it in
the repository and it was just done
basically to inform what's the
upperbound experience that you can get
using this protocol right so like what
what can we hope to achieve once we
productionalize this
>> and this ended up being a pretty common
theme I think in in my career from from
there on is like yeah sort of what is
this upperbound experience like
unbounded by any sort of constraints uh
and then yeah like how can we
productionalize it
>> yeah I'm curious because you said two
diffs in 6 months and it sounds like
there's a lot of risk and you are doing
a lot of things that may not be easy to
measure or prove the impact.
>> I think a lot of people be scared of
switching teams to especially to a risky
area like that. They worry their PSC
would look bad or something.
>> What was your performance review like in
in that half?
>> Yeah, I think that's there was it was
sort of in the job title where like
people who were hired on that team this
early on. it was sort of implied that
you know they get reviewed based on on
derrisking a lot of directions and not
necessarily like lending code. We also
again it's like the the team that was
sort of seated with like bunch of senior
people and so there was mutual
understanding that like it's going to be
taken care of. Um I think that this is
the way big tech sort of creates
incentives for people to come in into
those risky projects where you're not
guaranteed a promo but you're at least
protected from from from the downside,
right? because you want people who are
interested in taking risks to feel safe
and this is a lot of changes that
happened in in the PSC cycles over a
year where like first was sort of
optimized for half a year because you
kind of want to balance like feedback
that you get often but also you don't
want to to make sure you want to make
sure that people sort of feel safe
taking on the riskier bets that like
last you know maybe multiple halves and
so like it's it's delicate dance I
understand that everyone hates this
process but like I don't think there is
a good process per se that can be like
good for everyone.
>> I'm kind of curious because you I'm you
know mostly software engineering
initially and still like software but in
a hardware team. What's the biggest
difference you see between hardware
teams and software teams?
>> The timelines for sure. You it's this
fun sort of concept when you know back
in the day if you remember when uh
software would be still shipped on CDs
and in boxes. So you literally have to
put some bytes on the CD and and seal it
and send it to people, right? And so
with hardware, it is still the case that
at some point when you want to release
your gen one device, something has to go
to the factory to flush it onto the
device, right? And so this is why the
deadlines in the hardware projects are
so much more ruthless. You cannot push
them by one month. Everything falls
apart. And so it feels like this is
probably one of the key aspects. And
then yeah, you can have like zero day
updates when you like, you know, this
annoying thing when you just bought a
new device, you plug it in, it's like,
oh, sorry, I will take 20 hours to
update now. So like you can have that.
It's not a great experience, but you can
have it, but something has to go into
the box. And so this is the key
difference, especially in a company like
Meta where you have this continuous
software cycle that you don't even think
about. You know, you push something to
dubdubdub and it's instantly, you know,
within like three hours it's available
to like billions of people or like iOS
within a week. All this stuff hardware
makes you think in a very different
terms and it's like pretty chill at the
beginning, but then towards the end
there is a crunch time when like you
have to get it done by certain date and
that's quite different. So you had you
had the hardware teams and it sounds
like that was a lot of fun and then
eventually you went to a series of teams
that I'm really interested in because
they were cutting edge prototypes on
products that we know that launched. So
I want to hear the stories behind that.
What made you shift from hardware back
into these software teams specifically
focused on these rapid prototypes? So
the time has come for me to to try to
live outside of the US again for for a
bit. And again, Meta has this wonderful
um sort of flexibility of as long as
there is a business need, you know, in
engineering in in another office, you
can just move and sort of like work from
there. And so I really wanted to try to
live uh in London for for a bit. And I
was trying really hard to to stay on the
same team, the control apps team,
because it was just so much fun and
people were wonderful and technology was
so cool. But it's hardware. It's, you
know, especially having people uh living
abroad means that you have all sort of
potentially regulations with unreleased
technology like all sort of stuff that
you like I don't even know if that's the
case here, but I imagine that there is a
lot of complexity. And so I realized
that it's not going to be an option. And
so I needed to find a team in London
that uh would be happy to have me. And
as I learned uh Instagram was just about
to open the office in London. And so not
just any Instagram, it was Instagram
blockchain team. So for for for viewers
at home, Instagram used to have a
blockchain team. And you know for the
brief but glorious period of time, we
were building all sort of uh
technologies. So people pro might
remember that there was this whole
cryptoc currency effort that uh Meta
tried to to take off the ground that
eventually branched out into its own
sort of separate company. But then we we
had all the talent and technology built
in house uh to sort of to deal with uh
blockchain and crypto and all that. And
we basically thought about exploring
those directions um within Instagram
being creator first, creator forward
sort of product. Other products also
other sort of apps later joined uh as
well. But yeah, basically this team was
opening up in London and they were
looking for people to join and sort of
build out uh a bunch of stuff. So I
moved to London, joined this team and we
shipped sort of your vanilla NFT type of
product uh within Instagram where you
can upload your NFTs that would have
this like beautiful shimmering effect
and all that stuff. Eventually you you
were able to create NFTts from
Instagram. just like looking back at it
now like wow that's we used to have this
group internally called Facebook does
what and it was this internal group
where people posted screenshots of like
products they found inside of Facebook
app and it was like food delivery movie
tickets ordering like all sort of things
that people like Facebook does what now
and so this is like to me looking back
you know it was such a fun crazy moment
but yeah so I helped uh to ship the NFT
product but the actual thing that I was
working on that was really fun and
interesting to me. So at some point Adam
Maseri CEO of Instagram gave this TED
talk that was talking about how the
future of creators is decentralized and
he was sort of building on this idea how
right now as a creator you're sort of
bound to a certain platform to their you
know sort of policies to their whatever
contractual obligations but then if for
some reason you fall out of grace with
this platform you're banned all your
livelihood like if you build some sort
of followership it's all gone. So Maseri
gave this talk where he was exploring
this idea of like oh what if this notion
of follow following your creator exists
outside of any given platform and
platforms are there just to recognize
it. They can choose not to recognize it
but they they can choose to recognize
it. And so what exactly does it mean for
for Instagram? What exactly does it mean
for for creators for followers? And so I
was one of the people who was tasked to
just understand okay we have this TED
talk what does it mean as a product? And
so we found that basically we need to to
build a product that you know in order
for it to be successful we wanted to be
recognized by some other key players.
And so this is how I found myself being
uh embedded deep into partnership team
and working with uh people from Google,
Spotify, Shopify, Nike, all sort of
companies. And so we had a pretty like I
think that that exercise was super
interesting because not only I was sort
of prototyping the tech side of the
story of like okay like what does this
exactly mean? How how would Instagram
like what is my experience of I'm a
creator I'm on boarding onto Instagram
I'm a follower I'm coming to Instagram
and there is a creator that I already
follow on like I don't know Tik Tok or
elsewhere like how does it actually
happen that like do I connect my wallet
and then like we see some sort of like
token in there and we re like all sort
of open questions from from technology
standpoint but even more interestingly I
there were a lot of questions about sort
of business side of the story where you
have meta whose business is predicated
ated on ads. You have, let's say, I
don't know, Spotify whose business is
subscriptions. You have Shopify whose
business is, I guess, they charge
merchants for selling stuff. Um, and all
sort of like they're all different
incentives that all these companies
have. And so, how do you create a
product that they all are interested in
considering there are different business
incentives? And that was just really,
you know, as an engineer, you I think
you get to think about it either if you
run your own startup or if you're pretty
senior. I was neither of those things.
And like it was so fun to just go and
sort of play with it and uh yeah just
like meeting people from other companies
making a case for like oh this thing
should exist and like it is a really fun
exercise in seeing how you can convince
people that a product should exist
pretty much from scratch in a vacuum you
know like there is nothing and then
you're like oh yeah yeah it makes sense
for you business-wise and you know we we
got to various degrees of success with
different companies and then crypto
winter hit and we had to shut down the
entire project. But while it lasted, I
think that it sort of gave me a really
fun insight into this side of the story
where technology is important, but it's
so rare that companies uh sort of fall
apart. Well, I I don't know if it's
rare, but I feel like it's more often
than not the company companies fall
apart not because of technology. And so
there is this whole other aspect of
building a product that I think as
engineer engineers we don't often get
involved into but it's still a really
fun problem space to to think about.
>> Okay. So then crypto winter happened you
switched off that team and you started
work on a very experimental interesting
project Instagram threads.
>> Yeah.
>> Prior to its its launch. I'm curious
like how did you get recruited to that
team because that's a really you know
cool interesting 0ero to1 project. It
was sort of the writing was on the wall
that the whole like crypto efforts,
blockchain efforts will be no more. And
so sort of foreseeing that I ended up
helping people to ship some some pretty
traditional Instagram products uh for a
bit still from London and then a couple
of people reached out over Christmas
break as far as I remember and they
asked if I was familiar with uh sort of
activity pub this protocol behind
Masttodon so decentralized social
networking. I'm not up to this day I'm
not 100% sure why. I think that like you
know you sort of end up building some
some sort of credibility for prototyping
for like posting you know internally all
things that you do yada yada and so they
reached out they asked about it and I
was like oh yeah I'm kind of familiar
with that. I wasn't really big on
Masteron at any point but I was aware
that it's happening. I was sort of new
enough about it and then it was
Christmas break when I didn't really
have anything to do and I was in London
and what I did I spun off internal
instance of Instagram server and I
started looking into okay if I stand up
mastadon instance next to it within the
internal sort of network on mastadon you
can search and it finds users from any
other decentralized mastadon instance.
So they have this like protocol that
they talk to each other and they sort of
resolve all those names. And so I spun
off both of those instances and I wrote
a really simple and really horrible code
that was basically allowing internally
to resolve uh Instagram users from
Masteron. That was the first taste of
like cool we can actually get this stuff
we can get them talking to each other.
And you know it's not technically that
hard. Let's be honest. But what I found,
and this is probably another one of
those lessons where it's not about
technical complexity often times, it's
about having a concrete thing that you
can point at, you can give people to
play with it, you know, and and they can
actually see see it with their own eyes
and it creates so much momentum in the
project life, especially early on when
it's like, yeah, you can have like 500
decks or you can have like one prototype
that works and people can play with and
it just creates excitement and all of a
sudden people jump on the project and
like whatever. So that was the very
first thing. Again, it didn't really
derisk or move us anywhere because it
was obvious that it's possible, but it
just showed maybe the direction that
like, oh, I'm interested in the project
and I showed it to to the folks who
reached out. And then so the very next
step would be, okay, cool. Now we need a
mobile app. And I knew Instagram
codebase at the point relatively well
because I worked on Instagram blockchain
team for a bit. And so what I did, I
started stripping down the images from
Instagram app and just blowing up the
actual caption text to be pretty massive
and just hitting the same, you know,
internal Instagram server. And so it
would just show all the like my feed
without images and just with text. And I
was like, "Oh, cool. That that kind of
like, you know, you can squint and see
it." And then I worked with uh this
super talented guy, senior engineer, uh
Peter Cuttle, uh from Instagram. And
yeah, like the way he sort of knows back
end I feel like is sort of back of his
hand. Um, and so we had so much fun when
he was just building out the back end
stuff because he's way way better at
this obviously than than I am. And I was
just sort of like cool now will start
quering this new feed source that you
created that's going to have only this
special text post type and like
whatever. And so we started like sort of
chiseling out the mobile experience from
Instagram app and from the back end. So
we we sort of started with this here's
Instagram the way it exists today. Let's
start seeing how it can actually turn
into threads. Yeah. And so for a while
we had this as a secret sort of feature
gated to employees only inside of
Instagram. And it was yeah I think it
was like a pretty closed off project at
the beginning. So it was like gated uh
just to the team. We had this special
composer where you can type text because
in Instagram you cannot share a post
without an image. So we needed a way to
share a post without an image and like
back end
should survive you know this post that
doesn't have an image and not freak out
and like crash everywhere. So like
that's where Peter really uh helped
early on quite a bit and yeah we sort of
started chiseling this out and then I
ended up being this like iOS engineer
based in London when the rest of the
team started building up in um in New
York and and and NSF and yeah it was
sort of a fun journey from there from
there on. I was so London is what like I
don't know 8 hours ahead or five hours
like some number of hours ahead of New
York let's say and so wow I'm like
terrible at time zones but you wake up
in London time and it's super early and
because our builds were sort of separate
builds from Instagram app they would
constantly be broken because they were
not part of any continuous integration
yet and so like I would wake up all the
builds are broken I need to figure out
why is that someone would lend some code
doesn't include like our code paths
whatever so first three four hours you
just fix all the stuff you get it to
working and then team in the US wakes up
a bit later and they sort of they can
start working with it and then you build
out bunch of features as well and so
yeah it was it was a really fun process
we started hiring a bunch of people from
across the company it was a really fun
sort of project where it was just around
the time when Musk was acquiring Twitter
and so there was recognition that there
is this sort of window of opportunity if
there is some sort of chaotic moment in
the Twitter
then you know Meta can come up with with
its own product and so we needed to
build it in a way that at some point was
was ready to release and then we sort of
built on it so that you know you have
some usable version of it and you just
make sure that that doesn't fall apart.
Um yeah and so I think it it got built
in like five or 6 months if I remember
right from from this first prototype to
to releasing it to public and it was
yeah it was like one of those projects
where it is it was a top down incentive
sort of initiative uh from from um from
the leadership to get it working and
because of that all the red tape the
there would like magically people would
appear and they would be like let me
solve this for you and you're like yes
yes yes please and you just get to work
on on on the stuff that you care about.
It was so much fun and also it attracted
a lot of really talented people from
like all sort of um design product all
sort of stuff and yeah it was just
really really good collaboration people
that worked on that initial team they
were really stellar and then yeah there
would be surges of like invol like oh we
need to figure out integrity or privacy
or whatever performance you would just
sort of bring some people on board they
would like help you to figure out some
stuff it was a tremendous effort I think
that that became sort of a poster child
of a team at Meta to show how little you
can, you know, how little you need to
ship a great product. Granted, we built
it on Instagram. So, like we had super
high level primitives, scalable sort of,
you know, battle test and all that. So,
but yeah, it was it was something that
meta sort of I think tried to evangelize
later on. So, this is how we can build
products in this new environment. You
mentioned working with Peter, super
senior engineer at Instagram. What is
the thing that made him so uh great when
you worked with them?
>> I think that's he worked on it for so
long that he was familiar with all the
corners of the code and he sort of knew
well the consequence like what's the
fastest way to get post working without
an image, right? What's how to create a
new feed, how to like all those things.
he just sort of as if had answers to all
of that. And so it ended up being this
sort of like conversation between us to
early on and with more people later
where it's like oh cool like now we need
to figure out this piece and we just
have this conversation with code where
we like quickly land it. I'm I can test
against his back end and it just works.
And this is I mentioned it before. This
is something that's super super helpful
when you are when you want to move fast
whether it's prototyping or shipping
products. Familiarity with code gets you
a long way. And so meta is great because
it has this incredibly high level
primitives. So even when I would go and
work in the back end like dubdubdubdub
or or or Instagram or whatever, the size
of the primitives is so massive that you
it's so easy for you to be efficient. I
need to create a new entity and I don't
even need to know how privacy works. It
just gets the right defaults and it sort
of like ensures that nothing bad happens
and then you know then you there is a
way to customize it. But yeah, people
like Peter, they they just know stuff so
well. They know their their codebase so
well that like at this point I guess
like with all the AI advancements and
all that, you can see a future where you
just have a conversation with your
copilot type of AI and it sort of does
it for you. But that was roughly before
all of this AI craze happened and sort
of like became a norm. And so yeah,
Peter is like a co-pilot,
an incredible co-pilot.
Okay. So, he knows the company so well
that it's almost like you prompt him. He
just
>> But he doesn't hallucinate and that's
important.
>> Yeah.
>> I think one thing that's really
interesting to me in the story how you
got this opportunity. This is a really
cool team that you joined very um kind
of like cutting edge is it sounds like
you were already known as someone that
had these visible prototypes. Mh.
>> So they they came to you, but then not
only that, you just took some initiative
to just instantly start. It it doesn't
sound like they asked you to prototype.
You just
>> you replied with here's it working with
Mastadon and also here's another idea of
like a
>> you know bare bones like iOS app that's
kind of showing the vision.
>> Yeah.
>> So I feel like that's pretty interesting
takeaway. And I it sounds like your
prototypes too, they must not live in a
vacuum. It's not like you build it, it's
kind of like your curiosity. Sounds like
you build it and you share it and a lot
of people get excited about it and
you're already known as like a
prototyping person. Would you say that's
true?
>> Yeah, I think you know it's it's hard
for me to know for a fact reputation
that that I had at the time but maybe it
was around the same time when all the
sort of GPT early GPT sort of like was
coming out. So I was building a lot of
those things and sort of sharing them on
workplace. When you build something that
uses internal technology you can't
really post on Twitter, right? And so
you have to uh sort of do that uh
internally. But you know in exchange it
creates this perception of you know even
if you don't get like too high of an
engagement on your internal posts people
see them popping up and like eventually
they sort of build this mental model of
like oh yeah like if you want someone
like for like quick and dirty or like
whatever like prototyping that's that
that's the person to reach out and then
yeah I think responding with prototypes
instead of like oh yeah let me put this
on my you know to-do list. This just a
way that that shows the attitude like
early on in the in all those projects
you want people who who are not who
self-directed. I think that's what I
would be looking for at least. Yeah. And
and in the corporate world there is so
much alignment and you know like
meetings and all that. That's I think
that it always stands out when you have
someone taking you know initiative and
sort of like moving on in in the
ambiguity. And then after threads it
sounds like you mentioned that you
worked on a string of AI related
prototypes and transition away from that
and started working on you know meta and
stuff like that. Is there a you know
favorite prototype or maybe a story in
there that you think would be worth
talking about? Yeah, I think early on
there was one really fun pro fun it's
like a big word for it, but I built this
prototype that took all our public FAQ
about account safety and sort of like
all sort of things related to Facebook
accounts that you can find like in
facebook.com/help or whatever. And so we
took all of this and sort of rugged over
it. So like did retrieval augmented
generation over this information. And so
you can you can you don't have to search
for the specific answer. you can
actually just have a conversation with
this like AI was like I think it was
GPT3 time and so you can actually have a
conversation with it and it would
hallucinate like crazy but you can also
like see how it's getting there where
you can ground it in some sort of
concrete data and I posted it internally
and that was the only time when I got
number of reachouts from people from all
over the company that I never seen
before um it was like probably like
probably below 100 but about 50 and it
was people from all over the place that
recognized it like cool like all of a
sudden support is sort of like solved
not not really solved but like you know
you can see how it's moving into
direction where you can have customer
support being done way more efficiently
and and fast forward you can see so many
companies in the public right now
building those kind of products right so
and again it's not that I was first or
anything like that but it's just again
it's to the point where when you're in
your corporate sort of environment
you're grounded in internal technology
so much so much so that you are not even
aware of what's happening in the
industry and showing you know like
pulling in those pieces of industry and
grounding them in your internal data
technology tools whatever it really
helps to bring awareness within your
organization within within your company
too and you'll be surprised or maybe not
even surprised how often people you know
people have their lives and they don't
care to read Twitter every day and so
like they don't know what's like that
like oh here's this latest coolest thing
that like you know you can easily just
bring in those pieces of what's possible
right now into your corporate
environment and just keep people up to
date.
>> You know, when people talk about
visibility, you know, it's like, oh,
write up that says you moved this
metric, which is good, too. But it
sounds to me like a good prototype about
the right idea. It connects with people
in a way that writing can't, which is
like someone can click into it. Someone
can really
>> see. It's it's such a high throughput
thing rather than just text. So you got
the whole thing in front of you. Sounds
like that is a really good tool for
driving imagination of the future
direction alignment it sounds like on
hey this is this is a good we should
>> it yeah I think it goes back to to the
fidelity right so you have you can write
text and then it relies on both of us
being able to reconstruct what I meant
in your head and making sure that it's
like we actually align on on what I
meant that you build the same mental
model. You can draw an image and then
it's a bit easier. Video even easier.
Prototype is probably the highest
fidelity when there is like the less
ambiguity you leave to, you know, for
someone to interpret the better. And
then you can actually ground your
conversation in like, oh cool, like I
actually want this specific interaction
to be a bit better or different or
whatever. And you probably saw that
yourself so many times when you're in
the meeting and 20 minutes in you
realize that you were talking about
completely different product that's like
you you thought that you're building
together with this partner or whatever.
So it definitely helps a lot to to speed
up those ambiguous, you know, days of of
the project.
>> Okay. Well, coming to the end, I think
there's so many interesting reflections
we can have over this career cuz I think
your career is so unique in that I
remember you had written something or
said something like you got promoted
despite your best efforts not to and
like it was clearly not your your intent
to focus on career growth, more about
focusing on things you're building and
other circumstances. So, I'm kind of
curious like when it comes to career
growth, like looking back, if I recall
correctly, you were hired as a IC4.
Yeah.
>> Hired as IC4 and then were eventually
promoted to IC6, even though it was not
something you really even thought too
much about. What are your thoughts on,
you know, your career growth and also
like in switching teams as you go about
it? There was one friend who was on that
first newsfeed team that I joined who's
been there before I joined and who
stayed there throughout my entire time
at at Meta. He just left like maybe a
year ago. And so it's definitely way way
easier to level when you're in the same
space. You build connections, you build
goodwill, you build expertise, all those
things that help to propel your career
upwards. I think that yeah, I just
always found it a bit boring. Um, I
think coming from startups, coming from
outside of the US, my mentality was just
so not about that that I I just it took
me a while to conceptualize what PSC is
and like what is it for? Cuz like you're
at a startup, you get continuous
feedback every day, right? But here it
was sort of a bit different. I don't
view this as necessarily an advice that
you can scale and give to other people
that like, oh, do this thing and it's
going to be fun. No, like it really
depends on what you're optimizing for
and like what kind of career and life
you want to have. I do find that for
myself breaths is just a way to set
yourself up for those you know
connections that you build in the
future. So it's kind of like you you you
set yourself up with all the
connections, all the technology, all the
people and eventually some of them come
through and you know maybe you will take
a few wrong turns but as long as for me
personally as long as I enjoyed the
projects that I was working on and this
is what I was optimizing for the most. I
sort of wanted to work on projects that
I feel passionate about. I end up
working a lot. I used to work long hours
and to do that sustainably I needed to
enjoy what I'm doing and for me this joy
was coming definitely from fun more than
leveling and career growth. I mean it
sounds like the breath paid off as well
like there were many of the
opportunities that you got were because
you were kind of shooting shots
everywhere and people had seen that so
you cast a wide net.
>> Yeah, you definitely end up building
some sort of persona for for better and
for worse. I know that uh I have a few
really good friends on on infro teams
and we have this like ongoing jokes
about number of steps that I caused them
and like all the grief that I caused
them but like we're still friends and
and whenever they need to to to to know
how something is done in this completely
different corner of the app or or in
different app they come and ask right
and and it's helpful well not anymore
but they used to
>> you know when it comes to career advice
it's anecdotal and we can't really tell
what would have happened if you did
something differently we just kind of
interpret the dots looking back. But one
thing I was just thinking that might be
interesting is that boot camp class that
you joined for some reason everyone
stayed at the company the entire time
and they're completely different people
and it's also a low sample size but I'm
curious I don't know how much tabs you
kept on you know what they're doing and
how but when you compare your career to
theirs in terms of like what they worked
on and how theirs went you know do you
notice any differences?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, I know that a couple
start as I see became managers uh worked
in roughly the same space definitely
within the same apps. The other person
moved to reality labs and I think stayed
there for the entire time I think still
in IC. Yeah, I think they they all are
doing well but they definitely are kind
of people who prefer growing vertically
rather than just spreading themselves
all over the place.
So when I was leaving MEA, I felt that I
have to find someone to take over my
spot on the team. My last team was like
almost exclusively built around
prototyping within MAI. And it was hard.
And I'm not saying it to like pat myself
on the back, but I think that this is
something that large corporates, you
know, environments, they sort of
disincentivize against, you know, they
sort of like they don't make you want to
join to prototype to to to explore. And
I think that this is how you build
resilience in in bigger companies where
majority of people focusing on on your
impact and and you know all the all the
right stuff. But then you need someone
who is sort of like oh I'm just going to
take a risk and like see how that plays
out for no like you know not expecting
anything particular to happen. It also
kind of reminds me of like the
discussion of metrics versus uh I guess
vibes for lack of a better word is that
there's a lot of merit to that hyper
optimized way of thinking but it also is
the trap of like you know local maximums
and like you want if you want a
monotonically increasing number it's not
going to if you're not willing to take
the down you might not unlock like some
you know change.
>> Yeah. I think that there is definitely
something to be said about the good hard
law that the second you choose something
you elect this number to be a metric, it
ends up being a bad thing because people
end up sort of gaming it and so it stops
being a good metric, right? And so and
that is even before you sort of think
about the fact that many things are not
even measurable, right? And so you you
have to rely on the taste. You have to
rely on like whatever else to to build,
you know, good products to make sure
that yeah, you're not getting trapped in
the local maxima. It is hard. It is hard
especially. It's hard to to make a
framework out of it. I feel like for and
and large companies need frameworks
because nothing else scales. You did 10
teams in nine years. I'm curious looking
back on all of them. Is there any of
them that you the team switch you kind
of regretted? Um, or maybe it's like a
team switch where you thought, "Oh,
actually that one looking back maybe not
ideal."
>> I think that there were some that didn't
pay off as much as I was hoping to, but
I think in reality you sort of learn
from all of them. You learn something.
So, so that yeah, you going forwards you
at least try to avoid those sort of
lessons again. And in most cases again
you sort of like if you're a decent
person you work and you try your best
you end up just building at least good
relationship with people and going
forward those people can you know bring
you onto the next project or you bring
them or you know you just sort of end up
building a massive massive network. This
is something that I really only truly
appreciated once I left Meta is how many
people reached out and asked if they can
introduce me to people, asked what am I
doing. Bunch of people reached out and
asked if I can hire them into this thing
that I'm doing which I don't know what
it is yet. It is definitely a really
really fun adventure and you get to meet
so many cool people that it's just hard
to to overestimate. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I I had never worked directly with
you, but I knew of you. So clearly what
you had done cast a very wild.
>> Yeah, it's it's wild to me when people
reach out. They used to reach out on
work chat and they would be like, "Oh,
hey, we like talked, you know, in 2020."
And my memory is also horrible. And so I
just I I rarely remember things that
happened like more than a year ago. I
always feel terrible, but I also feel
so, you know, humbled by like, oh my
god, people know. This is so cool. It's
really fun. Now you've left Meta. What
was the rationale for leaving Meta
rather than doing another team switch?
>> Yeah, I think that's well it's been a
really long time and I started in
startups and I felt like I wanted to go
back to this space where you know pace
at which I prefer to move is the natural
pace. So you know you you end up taking
on far more risk financially makes no
sense. Uh practically makes no sense.
But right now I have few ideas that I'm
exploring you know and I'm sort of like
passionate about and at this point there
is no meeting there is no partner team
that I can blame on the failure. It's
like you're so close to the wire that
you just you try it out and you see if
it works and then again it's it's a big
tech you know you can always come back
and like be hired into the next big tech
company and and it's all going to be
fine hopefully. But it is definitely a
fun experiment to see how much what is
your actual worth, you know, what are
your ideas and all those things that you
thought you you can deliver on like can
you actually do that? So I think it's
going to be an interesting exercise.
We'll see.
So it sounds like you laughed because uh
you wanted to go even deeper into like
prototyping and like doing your own
thing and being unbounded and it's a
two-way door, not a one-way door. You
can always crack. Yeah, that's that's
the way it's it's a really good
framework that someone uh mentioned
before that you need to think really
carefully when you enter a one-way door.
When it's a two-way door, or at least it
looks like one, you need to be concerned
and like sort of careful, but also take
a risk while you can. Yeah. And I'm sort
of like still in in in the place in my
life where I'm lucky enough to to be
able to take some risks. And then last
thing is looking back on your career and
if you were to talk to yourself when you
had just entered the industry and you
could give yourself some advice, what
would that thing be that you tell
yourself? Yeah, I think that's one thing
that uh one of my managers told me and I
think it's coming from one of the the
consultancy frameworks where you know at
first I honestly thought that I need to
fix all my shortcomings, fix all the
things that I'm I'm sort of like softer
at and my manager told me you want to
make sure that they don't get in your
way but you really want to focus on your
strengths and so I think that that was a
relatively eye openening as as obvious
as it is, it was a relatively eye
opening sort of advice. You want to
position yourself where you can showcase
your strength and when you where your
weaknesses are not getting in your way.
I think that's whatever that means in
your case, this is probably how you're
going to be the most successful long
term. Yeah, that reminds me of something
that a VP had written early Facebook and
he said something like one of the big
learnings was that the value in where
the real impact come from is not from
taking something that's poor and
bringing it to passable but taking
something that's great and making it
excellent. Thanks for taking the time to
ask. I was really, you know, looking
forward to it and um is there anything
you want to uh say to the audience? No,
I think you can find me on Twitter. I'll
probably be sharing more about uh stuff
that I'm building on there. And yeah,
thanks so much for inviting and having
over. It's it's been a lot of fun to to
chat and reflect on all this stuff.
>> Hey, thanks for watching the show. I
don't sell anything or do sponsorships,
but if you want to support, you can
subscribe on YouTube or you can leave a
review on Spotify. And I'm always
looking for new guests to interview. So,
if anyone comes up who you think you
really want to hear their career story,
uh, let me know and I'll try to reach
out to them and get them on the show.
Thanks for listening as always and I'll
see you next